Guide to the Charles Wesley Andrews Papers, 1808-1901
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Charles Wesley Andrews papers 1808-1901
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Andrews, C. W. (Charles Wesley), 1807-1875.
3,640 Items
Protestant Episcopal clergyman, Shepherdstown, W. Va.
Correspondence, journal (in letter form) of travels in Europe and the Near East in the 1840s, and other papers relating to church affairs, to the American Colonization Society, to conditions in Virginia before, during, and after the Civil War, and to such schools as the Episcopal High School and the Theological Seminary at Alexandria, Va., Woodberry Forest School, Orange, Va., Washington College (now Washington and Lee), Va., Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, and others. Includes genealogical material on the Meade, Page, Custis, Fitzhugh, Robinson, Mines, and Boteler familes of Virginia.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charles Wesley Andrews Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1956.
Biographical Note
Protestant Episcopal clergyman, Shepherdstown, W. Va.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, journal (in letter form) of travels in Europe and the Near East in the 1840s, and other papers relating to church affairs, to the American Colonization Society, to conditions in Virginia before, during, and after the Civil War, and to such schools as the Episcopal High School and the Theological Seminary at Alexandria, Va., Woodberry Forest School, Orange, Va., Washington College (now Washington and Lee), Va., Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, and others. Includes genealogical material on the Meade, Page, Custis, Fitzhugh, Robinson, Mines, and Boteler familes of Virginia.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Andrews, C. W. (Charles Wesley), 1807-1875
Boteler family
Custis family
Fitzhugh family
Mead family
Mines family
Page family
Robinson family
American Colonization Society
Episcopal Church -- Virginia -- History
Episcopal High School of Virginia
Kenyon College
Washington and Lee University
Woodberry Forest School
African Americans -- Colonization -- Africa
Religious education
Europe -- Description and travel
Virginia -- Education -- History
Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
Virginia -- Social conditions
West Virginia -- Social conditions
Contents of Collection
- Charles Wesley Andrews Papers, 1808-1901, (14 boxes)
  - Letters, 1808-1842 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1843-1852 (Box 2)
  - Letters, 1853-1860 (Box 3)
  - Letters, 1861-1865 (Box 4)
  - Letters, 1866-1879 (Box 5)
  - Letters, 1880-1923 & undated (Box 6)
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1820s-1830s
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1850s (Box 7)
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1850s-1860s (Box 8)
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1860s-1870s (Box 9)
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1870s-1890s & undated (Box 10)
  - Clippings, printed material (Box 11)
  - Volumes (Box 12)
  - Volumes (Box 13)
  - Miscellany (Box 14)